Register of the Gilchrist Baker Stockton Papers, 1911-1959.
Hoover Institution Archives
Gilchrist Baker Stockton Papers,
1911-1959.
75030
Stockton, Gilchrist Baker, 1890-1973.
11 manuscript boxes (4.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, dispatches, reports, clippings, and photographs, relating to activities of the Commission for Relief in Belgium, 1915-1916, and of the American Relief Administration in Austria, 1919-1933; and to establishment of the Jacksonville, Florida, Naval Air Base.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1975.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Commission for Relief in Belgium (1914-1930); American Relief Administration. European Children's Fund.; United States. Naval Air Base (Jacksonville, Florida); International relief.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Austria.; World War, 1914-1918--Belgium.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; Austria.; Austria--Foreign relations--United States.; Belgium.; Belgium--History--German occupation, 1914-1918.; Florida--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Foreign relations--Austria.; United States--Politics and government--1923-1929.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Diplomats--United States.
Biographical Notes.
1890, August 20 Born, Jacksonville, Florida
1914 B. Litt., Princeton University
1917 B.A., Oxford University (Rhodes Scholar)
1927 M.A., Oxford University
1915-1916 Staff, Commission for Relief in Belgium
1916-1917 Special Assistant to U.S. Ambassador, London
1917-1919 Aide to Admiral William S. Sims
1919-1920 Chief of Mission, American Relief Administration, Austria
1917-1950 U.S. Naval Reserve
1928 Delegate from Florida to Democratic National Convention
1930-1933 U.S. Minister to Austria
1945 Rear Admiral, U.S. Naval Reserve
Container List
- Correspondence, 1911-1940. (Box No. 1-3.)
  Correspondence arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Blount, Margaret Stockton, 1919 (Box 1.)
  - Braxton, Carter M., 1923-1924
  - Brown, Walter Lyman, 1920-1923
  - Bryan, Judge Nathan P., 1928
  - Buchholz, F. W., 1923-1926
  - Burland, E. G., 1930
  - Carlton, Governor Doyle E., 1929
  - Cates, Mr. and Mrs. Fred S., 1921-1930
  - Causey, Colonel W. B., 1920-1930
  - Chase, J. C., 1927-1930
  - Colt, John, 1922-1929
  - Cotton, Joseph P., 1930
  - Crawford, John T. G., 1928-1929
  - Croft, Alfred, 1923
  - Curtis, Edward D., 1916-1922
  - Davis, John W., 1924
  - Dean, S. Bobo, 1928-1930
  - Fletcher, Senator Duncan U., 1930
  - Follest, Adaline, 1919
  - Frank, Nancie Crosse, 1918-1923
  - Fraser, A. M., 1925
  - Galpin, Perrin C., 1920-1930
  - Gibson, Hugh, 1918-1930
  - Godwin, Mr. and Mrs. J. Walker, 1922-1930
  - Good, Paul F., 1924
  - Graves, John Temple, 1923-1925
  - Graves, John Temple, II, 1913-1930
  - Hathaway, Fons A., 1925-1928 (Box 2.)
  - Hoover, President Hebert, 1928-1929
  - Hughes, John C., 1914-1930
  - Hurley, Patrick, 1930
  - Jones, Jesse H., 1924
  - Kelly, Mrs. D. F., 1922-1925
  - Kirby, F. M., 1923-1924
  - Knight, Colonel Peter O., 1927-1928
  - Lesan, H. E., 1928-1930
  - McEachin, Thomas C., Jr., 1922-1924
  - McMullen, Donald C., 1929
  - McQuaid, W. R., 1926
  - Mann, Colonel H. A., 1928
  - Martin, Governor John W., 1925-1927
  - Messinger, Carl, 1922-1925
  - Milton, George Fort, 1928-1930
  - Miscellaneous, 1917-1930
  - Murphee, A. A., 1923
  - Nicoll, Mrs. DeLancey, 1918-1925
  - Owen, Representative Ruth Bryan, 1926-1930
  - Pole, J. W., 1929
  - Reichner, L. Irving, 1925
  - Richardson, Gardner, 1933-1939
  - Richardson, R. N. D., 1918
  - Rickard, Edgar, 1921
  - Rosenthal, Benjamin J., 1921
  - Seitz, President Karl, 1920
  - Sims, Admiral William S., 1919-1930
  - Skipper, G. B., 1929
  - Stark, Admiral Harold R., 1940
  - Stockton, Mr. and Mrs. John N. C., 1914-1922 (Box 3.)
  - Stockton, William T., 1911-1930
  - Terry, General M. O., 1924
  - Torrey, Clare M., 1919-1930
  - Twining, N. C., 1919
  - Ulmer, Jean Stockton, 1916-1919
  - Yarnell, Admiral Harry Ervin, 1940
- Subject File, 1912-1959. (Box No. 4-11.)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, clippings, photographs, printed matter, telegrams, dispatches, and miscellanea, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Business, 1922-1929 (Box 4.)
    - Jacksonville Landscape Company, 1926-1928
    - Jacksonville Real Estate Board, 1922-1928
    - Mid-State Waterway Association, 1924-1925
    - Miscellaneous, 1926-1929
  - Charitable Organizations, 1924-1927
    - American Red Cross (Jacksonville Chapter), 1924
    - Children's Home Society of Florida, 1924
    - Community Chest Association (Jacksonville and Duval County), 1924-1927
  - Diplomatic Service, 1916-1933
    - U.S. Embassy, London, 1916-1919
    - U.S. Embassy, Vienna, 1930-1933
      - Congratulatory letters upon appointment as U.S. minister to Austria, 1930
      - Dispaches to U.S. State Department, May 26, 1930 to April 27, 1932 (Box 5.)
      - Dispatches to U.S. State Department, May 4, 1932 to September 7, 1933 (Box 6.)
      - Telegrams to and from U.S. State Department, 1930-1933 (Box 7.)
  - Personal, 1917-1930
    - Congratulatory letters upon marriage, 1925
    - Diary fragments, 1917
    - Miscellaneous, 1926-1930
  - Politics, 1923-1930
    - Applicants for federal appointments, 1929-1930
      - Borden, Mrs. N. B., 1929
      - Carswell, Joseph P., 1929
      - Cisco, B. R., 1929
      - Greeley, Allan, 1929
      - Sasnett, R. M., Jr., 1930
      - Smith, Hill A., 1929
    - Democratic National Convention of 1924, Florida primary to elect delegates
      - Clippings and printed matter
      - Correspondence
        - Baxter, E. G.
        - Broome, W. S.
        - Brown, Max M.
        - Butler, J. Turner
        - Carn, B. O.
        - Carter, Francis B.
        - Carter, Jerry W.
        - Clarke, S. D.
        - Coleman, Dr. W. E.
        - Cone, Dr. D. N.
        - Cone, F. P.
        - Cone, W. B.
        - Davis, T. H.
        - Dearing, F. P.
        - Frink, Russell L.
        - Geiger, L. L.
        - Hampton, Hilton S.
        - Hampton, William Wade, Jr.
        - Harris, Al
        - Henderson, Robert A., Jr.
        - Huffaker, R. B.
        - Igou, D. R.
        - Ingram, F. P.
        - Jones, Charles E.
        - Layton, C. R.
        - Lindsay, David B.
        - Lowry, Sumter L., Jr.
        - Lucas, Thomas E.
        - Macfarlane, Hugh C.
        - May, Phil S.
        - Milliner, R. L.
        - Miscellaneous
        - Mullen, Charles G.
        - Myers, W. Blount
        - Payne, T. C.
        - Phifer, J. A.
        - Phillips, Herbert S.
        - Phillips, W. F.
        - Raney, George P.
        - Reaves, O. K.
        - Rouse, William C.
        - Sawyer, Herbert S.
        - Shackleford, T. M., Sr.
        - Stewart, Judge J. B.
        - Stockton, William T.
        - Stokes, G. H.
        - Straub, W. L.
        - Sutton, John B.
        - Swearingen, John J.
        - Terrell, Justice Glenn
        - Turner, Robert O.
        - Watson, W. H.
        - Wells, H. H.
        - West, Justice Thomas F.
        - Wideman, Jerome E.
        - Wilson, B. C.
        - Young, Fred H.
      - Expense Statements
    - Democratic National Convention of 1928
      - Florida primary to elect delegates
        - Campaign announcements and literature
        - Correspondence
          - Crawford, H. Clay
          - Froscher, N. T.
          - Graves, John Temple II
          - Harrington, Sadette
          - McAdoo, William G.
          - Miscellaneous
          - Othen, John
          - Shaver, Clem
          - Stewart, Judge J. B.
          - Tanner, Lois K. Mayes
          - Thorn, George D.
        - Expense statements
        - Notes, results, etc.
      - National convention
        - Convention rules reform
        - Rosters of delegates, etc.
    - Duval County, Florida, Board of County Commissioners, Highway assessment districts, 1926-1927 (Box 8.)
    - Florida Anti-Tammany League, correspondence, 1928
      - L'Engle, E.J.
      - Wolf, John H.
    - Florida State Legislature, 1927
      - Correspondence with John Temple Graves II
      - General, n.d.
    - League of Nations Non-Partisan Association, 1923-1925 Correspondence, 1923-1925
      - Aydelotte, Frank, 1923
      - Pepper, Senator George Wharton, 1924
      - Wiegart, Marie W., 1925
      - Printed matter, 1923
    - Miscellaneous, 1927-1928
      - Flint, Dorothea Paradise, "What Woodrow Wilson Means to Me."
      - General, 1927-1928
  - Relief work, 1915-1929
    - American Relief Administration. European Children's Fund. Austria, 1919-1922
      - Clippings and translations of clippigs, 1919-1920
      - Correspondence, 1919-1920
        - Allen, Mrs. Lloyd, 1920
        - Baker, George Barr, 1919-1920
        - Beckley, Zoe, n.d.
        - Brown, Walter Lyman, 1919-1920
        - Bucher, A. J., n.d.
        - Causey, Colonel W. B., n.d.
        - Embree, Edwin R., 1920
        - Fuller, W. P. Jr., 1919-1920
        - Geist, Dr. R. Hermann, 1919
        - Griffith, James E., 1919
        - Gruneberger, Dr. N., 1920
        - Hynes, John H., 1920
        - Kellogg, Dr. Vernon, 1920
        - Khittel, Josef, 1920
        - Klastersky, Herr, 1920
        - Loewenthal, Dr. Josef, 1920
        - Miscellaneous, 1920
        - Mott, J. R., 1920
        - Pirquet, Dr. Clemens, 1920
        - Powers, Edwin, 1920
        - Quinn, Captain C. J. C., 1920
        - Reumann, Jakob, 1920
        - Shaler, Millard K., 1920
        - Simpson, John Lowrey, 1920
        - Strother, French, 1920
        - Swing, Raymond, n.d.
        - Vickrey, C. V., 1920
        - Viereck, George Sylvester, 1919
        - Whitestone, S. L., 1920
        - Yarnall, D. Robert, 1920
      - Memoranda, 1919-1920
        - General, 1920
        - Regarding Dr. R. Hermann Geist, 1919-1920
      - Messages of gratitude for relief work, 1920
      - Miscellaneous, 1919-1922
      - Speech by Sir William Goode, "The Plight of Central Europe and a Possible Remedy,' 1919
      - Telegraphic dispatches, 1919-1920
    - American Relief Administration Association, 1923-1929
      - Correspondence, 1928-1929
        - Cox, Dr. John, 1928
        - Hutchinson, Dr. Lincoln, 1929
        - Tuthill, Marshall W., 1929
        - Wright, Robert C., 1928
      - General, 1923-1929
    - Commission for Relief in Belgium, 1915-1925
      - Correspondence, 1915-1925
        - Curtis, Edward D., 1915
        - Hollmann, J. J., 1915
        - Rickard, Edgar, 1923-1925
        - Simpson, R. H., 1916
        - Whitlock, Brand, 1915
      - General, 1915-1925 (Box 9.)
      - Manuscripts, untitled
      - Reports, 1915
        - "Report on the Deputation Permanente of Antwerp"
        - Warren, Robert H., "Statement of Circumstances Leading up to and Attending My Arrest at Esschen on Saturday, April 24th, 1915"
    - Social organizations, 1922-1930
      - Civitan Club of Jacksonville, 1924-1930
      - Friars Club, 1922-1926
      - Ortega Riding Club, 1927-1929
    - U.S. Navy, 1917-1959
      - General, 1917-1959
        - Correspondence, 1934-1959
          - Adams, Dr. Thomas S., 1940
          - Allen, Rear Admiral William H., 1938-1939
          - Angas, Commander W. Mack, 1939-1940
          - Ashby, Clarence G., 1952
          - Ashby, Clarence Garnett, Jr., 1952
          - Cummer, Wellington W., 1939
          - Daniel, Lieutenant Jacquelin J., 1945
          - DeWolf, Captain M. M., 1945-1946
          - Ferguson, Lieutenant Commander Robert R., 1934
          - Forrestal, James V., 1945
          - Fortson, Commander R. Malcolm, 1936-1941
          - Graves, John Temple, II, 1944
          - Gygax, Captain Felix, 1938
          - Kimball, Dan A., 1952
          - Lampe, Commander A. E., 1945
          - Lynch, Captain J. B., 1944
          - McFall, Rear Admiral A. C., 1945
          - Price, Captain John Dale, 1943
          - Schuyler, Captain G. L., 1940
          - Smith, Captain L., 1959
          - Spears, Captain W. O., 1936-1938
          - Walrath, Lieutenant L. K., 1943
          - Weaver, Major Lamar, 1939
        - Manuscript, "The Naval Reserve Force."
        - Orders, memoranda, fitness reports, etc., 1917-1954.
      - Jacksonville, Florida, Naval Air Base, 1938-1949
        - Clippings, 1939-1941
        - Correspondence, 1938-1949
          - Adair, Henry P., 1939
          - Adler, Colonel Julius, 1939
          - Andrews, Senator Charles O., 1939-1940
          - Angas, Robert M., 1939
          - Barber, Colonel A. B., 1939
          - Barton, Representative Bruce, 1939
          - Bell, R. J., 1940
          - Bennett, Walter J., 1939
          - Bishop, M. W., 1941
          - Blume, G. C., 1939
          - Butts, Elliot W., 1939
          - Carter, Fae R., 1939
          - Cary, James G., 1939
          - Chase, Joshua C., 1939
          - Clark, James B., 1939
          - Clason, Representative Charles R., 1939
          - Coachman, Walter F., Jr., 1939
          - Cole, Representative W. Sterling, 1939
          - Cone, Admiral Hutch I., 1939
          - Cotter, Commander Carl H., 1939-1940
          - Cushman, Raymond W., 1939
          - Daniels, James T., 1939
          - DeHoff, William J., 1949
          - Edison, Charles, 1939
          - Estes, Nieuport B., 1939
          - Fortson, Commander R. Malcolm, 1939
          - Gamble, Robert H., 1940-1941
          - George, Senator Walter F., 1939
          - Green, Representative Lex, 1939
          - Hoit, Richard B., 1939
          - Imeson, Thomas C., 1939
          - Jones, W. D., Jr., 1939-1941
          - Kassewitz, Samuel, 1939
          - Kavanaugh, J. E., 1939
          - Knox, Captain D. W., 1939
          - Lowry, Brigadier General Sumter L., Jr., 1939
          - Mason, Captain C. P., 1941 (Box 10.)
          - Matthews, Eugene S., 1939
          - Meade, Lieutenant Commander R. H., 1941
          - Milam, Arthur Y., 1939-1940
          - Milam, Robert R., 1939
          - Miscellaneous, 1939-1941
          - Moreell, Admiral Ben, 1939-1940
          - Murchison, Charles H., 1939
          - Newton, Walter H., 1939
          - Patten, George L., 1939
          - Pepper, Senator Claude, 1938-1939
          - Porcher, Arthur G., 1939
          - Reamy, H. J., 1940
          - Regan, Captain H. E., 1945
          - Register, J. Alvin, 1939
          - Sanders, Gold V., 1939
          - Smith, C. Sweet, n.d.
          - Stark, Admiral Harold R., 1941
          - Steiner, Ensign R. L., 1941
          - Stockton, James R., 1939
          - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays, 1939
          - Tomb, Captain James H., 1939-1940
          - Towers, Jack, 1940
          - Ulmer, Herman, 1939
          - Watkins, Colonel Lewis H., 1939
          - West, Helen, 1939
          - Wiles, Frank, 1939
          - Williams, V. O., 1939
          - Wilson, Captain James Y., 1939
          - Yarnell, Rear Admiral Harry Ervin, 1941
        - Maps and blueprints
        - Memoranda, reports, miscellanea, 1938-1947
          - "Comparative Advantages of Establishing a Major Navy Air Base at Jacksonville and Miami," 1939
          - Deegan, William J., Jr., "Naval Air Base, Fernandina, Florida," 1939
          - Dozier, Lieutenant (junior grade) Louis S., "Statement by... at Deland, Florida on 28 February 1940."
          - General, 1939-1947
            - Miscellaneous, 1939-1941
            - Regarding bus transportation to naval base, 1939-1947
          - Leahy, Admiral William D., "Statement of the Chief of Naval Operations before the Senate Naval Affairs Committee in Connection with S-830, 6 March 1939."
          - "Memorandum Regarding Southeastern Air Base."
          - "Report on Hearings on Air Base, February 3, 1939," U.S. House of Representatives.
          - Sandquist, Lieutenant Commander O. A., "Supplemental Engineering Report," 1939
          - U.S. Engineer Office, "Estimates of Cost: Channel, Turning Basin, Bulkhead, Fill, Dike, Causeway, and Jetties for Potential Naval Air Base at Key Biscayne, near Miami, Florida," 1939
          - U.S. Engineer Office, "Estimates of Cost of Channels, Basins and Docks for Potential Naval Air Bases in St. Johns River near Jacksonville, Florida" 1938
        - Printed matter - Congressional bills, committee reports, etc., 1939
    - Universities, 1912-1930 (Box 11.)
      - Oxford University, 1912-1929
        - Academic records, 1912-1928
        - Oxford Officers Training Corps, 1917
        - Rhodes Scholarships, 1921-1929
          - Dacy, G. H., "Florida's Rhodes Scholars at Oxford."
          - General, 1921-1929
      - Princeton University alumni association, 1921-1930
    - Veterans Organizations, 1922-1930
      - American Legion. Edward C. DeSaussure Post #9, Jacksonville, Florida, 1922-1930
        - Charter and by-laws, 1923
        - General, 1923-1930
        - Resolutions, 1922-1924
          - Adjusted Compensation Bill (Bonus Bill), 1922-1924
          - Convict Lease System, 1923
          - General, n.d.
          - Immigration Restriction, 1923
          - Ku Klux Klan, 1923
      - Navy and Marine Memorial, 1924-1925
      - La Societe des 40 Hommes et 8 Chevaux, 1923-1924
      - U.S. Veterans Bureau, 1922-1924